Jack Burkhardt

Chicago, Illinois, United States



mail@jackburkhardt.com



linkedin.com/in/jack-burkhardt



(312) 478-9592



https://jackburkhardt.com/

Summary

I'm a freshman at Northwestern University studying the intersection between Computer Science and Psychology. My interests include information systems, hardware design, sociology, and game design. I want to create technology that makes the lives of other people easier, better, and more enjoyable.

I have a strong background in computers and servers, in both software and hardware, and experience ranging from setup to maintenance to troubleshooting. I also have recent job experience in retail customer support, which involved using multiple large electronic systems to provide accurate service.

Experience



Special Services Associate

The Home Depot

May 2020 - Present (10 months +)

- Generated \$10,000+ in sales for my store while reducing order pick times and increasing pick accuracy, and received Homer awards for doing so
- Worked with HD's electronic systems to manage customer orders, information, and store inventory
- Handled customer service, sales, returns, delivery scheduling, and order picking, often doing multiple duties simultaneously

Freelance System Administration

Freelance, self-employed

Sep 2017 - Present (3 years 6 months +)

Purchased and set up several dedicated servers for hobby use and hosting

- Hosted and/or developed for over 30 different gameservers
- Created and maintained multiple personal, business, and community websites with software including Wordpress, Mediawiki, and LAMP
- Used tools such as Docker and bash scripting to enhance workflow



Volunteer

FREEGEEK CHICAGO NFP

Sep 2018 - Mar 2020 (1 year 7 months)

- Tore down donated technology and responsibly recycled materials
- Tested salvaged parts for reusability, reducing e-waste produced
- Constructed new computers using recycled parts and sold at a low price, making computers more accessible

Student Mentor at CodeDay Chicago

CodeDay

Nov 2019 - Dec 2020 (1 year 2 months)

- Worked with other mentors and venue staff to make sure events ran smoothly, and on schedule but was a fun and educational experience for attendees
- Advised teams during both proposal and development phases, encouraging them to expose themselves to new technologies and strategies

Event Coordinator

Chicode

Dec 2018 - Jun 2020 (1 year 7 months)

- Founded and organized the annual Jones Jam 12 hour hackathon, hosting over 80 attendees and 15 volunteers
- Managed planning, logistics, and training for activities and workshops while preparing event volunteers and speakers
- Led fundraising and advertising campaigns that stretched across the Chicago Public Schools system

Education



Northwestern University

Bachelor of Arts - BA, Computer Science 2020 - 2024



Jones College Prep

High School Diploma

2016 - 2020

- Enrolled in all Honors level or Advanced Placement classes
- Founder and leader of both the school Robotics club/team and Computer Science club
- Recipient of Jones Computer Science Award
- Jones College Prep High Honor Roll (2016-2020)

Skills

Linux System Administration • Adobe Creative Suite • Event Management • Adobe Premiere Pro • Web Hosting • Fast Learner • Game Development • Customer Service